Rohan French



Institutional Address

Faculty of Philosophy University of Groningen Oude Boteringestraat 52 9712 GL Groningen - The Netherlands E-MAIL: rohan.french@gmail.com URL: http://rohan-french.github.io SKYPE: rohan.french

DATE OF BIRTH: January 31, 1984 NATIONALITY: Australian

AREAS OF SPECIALIZATION

Philosophical Logic • Philosophy of Logic • Metaphysics

AREAS OF COMPETENCE

Formal Logic • Philosophy of Language • Epistemology.

CURRENT POSITION

2015-Present

Postdoctoral Researcher working with Catarina Dutilh Novaes on the "Roots of Deduction" project in the Department of Theoretical Philosophy in the Faculty of Philosophy at the University of Groningen on formal aspects of the built-in opponent conception of deduction.

PREVIOUS POSITIONS

2014

Visiting Research Scholar, at Center for the Advancement of Logic, its Philosophy, History & Applications and Department of Logic and Philosophy of Science, University of California Irvine. (Winter Quarter)

2013-2015

Research Assistant for Greg Restall at the University of Melbourne working on Coursera courses https://class.coursera.org/logic1-001/ and https://class.coursera.org/logic1-001/ and https://class.coursera.org/logic2-001/.

2011-2013

Research Associate, Department of Philosophy & Bioethics, Monash University.

Education

2007-2011

Ph.D. in Philosophy

Department of Philosophy and Bioethics, Monash University.

- Title: "Translational Embeddings in Modal Logic"
- Degree Awarded: 17th January 2011
- · Advisors: Graham Oppy, Lloyd Humberstone
- Examiners: Alasdair Urquhart (Toronto), Stephen Kuhn (Georgetown).

2002-2006

Bachelor of Arts (Hons)/Bachelor of Computer Science, Monash University

Grants, Honors & Awards

Dean's Award for Best Sessional Teacher in the School of Philosophical, Historical and International Studies

Monash Research Graduate School Postgraduate Publication Award
 Australian Research Council (ARC) Postgraduate Research Scholarship
 Camo Jackson Award for Best Honours in Philosophy, Monash University

2005 Scholarship to attend Australian National University (ANU) Logic Summer School

Publications & Talks

IOURNAL ARTICLES

201X	1. French, R. and Ripley, D., "Contractions of Noncontractive Consequence Relations", forthcom-
	ing in Review of Symbolic Logic. [DOI]

- 20. French, R., "Sequent Calculi for Urn Logic", *The Journal of Logic, Language and Information* Vol. 24, 131–147. [DOI]
- 3. French, R. and Humberstone, L., "An Observation Concerning Porte's Rule in Modal Logic", The Bulletin of the Section of Logic 44:1/2, 25–31.
- 4. French, R., "In the Mood for **S4**: The Expressive Power of the Subjunctive Modal Language in Weak Background Logics", *Studia Logica*, Vol. 103, 239–263. [DOI]
- 5. French, R., "Review of A.A. Rini and M. J. Cresswell 'The World-Time Parallel'", Australasian Journal of Philosophy, Vol. 92, 802-805. [DOI]
- 6. French, R., "Expressive Power, Mood, and Actuality", Synthese, Vol. 190, 1689-1699. [DOI]
- 7. French, R. (2012), "Denumerably Many Post-Complete Normal Modal Logics with Additional Propositional Constants", *Notre Dame Journal of Formal Logic*, Vol. 53, 549-556.
- 8. French, R. (2012), "An Argument Against General Validity?", Thought, Vol. 1, 4-9.
- 9. French, R. and Humberstone, L. (2009), "Partial Confirmation of a Conjecture on the Boxdot Translation in Modal logic", *Australasian Journal of Logic*, Vol. 7, 56–61.
- 10. French, R. (2009), "A Simplified Embedding of **E** into Monomodal **K**", Logic Journal of the IGPL, Vol. 17, 421–428, 2009.
- 2008 11. French, R. (2008), "The Logic of Eventual Permanence for Unending Linear Time", The Notre Dame Journal of Formal Logic, Vol. 49, No 2, 137–142

TALKS

- Sept 2015* Osnabrück, "Structural Reflexivity and the Semantic Paradoxes", German Society for Analytic Philosophy (GAP.9)
- Aug 2015* Helsinki, "Hypersequents for Contingent Existence", 15th Congress on Logic, Methodology and the Philosophy of Science.
- Sept 2014 Melbourne, w. Lloyd Humberstone "Thomas Forster on Definite Descriptions", Melbourne Logic Group Logic Day.
- May 2014 Melbourne, "Modal Logics with Statability Operators: Variations on a Priorian Theme", Melbourne Logic Group Logic Day.
- Feb 2014 U.C. Irvine, "Predicate Logic with Explicit Scope Markers", UC Irvine Logic and Philosophy of Science Colloquium.
- Nov 2013 Melbourne, "Predicate Logic with Explicit Scope Markers", Melbourne Logic Group Logic Day.
- Nov 2012 Monash, "The Ontological Innocence of Mereology", Monash Workshop on the Metaphysics of Time.
- Sept 2012 Melbourne, "Sequent Calculi for Urn Logic", Melbourne Logic Group.
- June 2012 Sydney, "Kaplan's Monsters-The Case of Fixedly", Australasian Association of Logic Conference.
- June 2012 Melbourne, "Proof Theory for Contingent Existence", Melbourne Logic Group.

Apr 2012	U.C. Irvine, "In the Mood for S4", Invited presentation at Workshop on Actuality and Subjunctivity
	organised by K.F. Wehmeier.
Nov 2011	Kioloa, "The Logical Argument Against Quantifier Variance", Australian Metaphysics Conference.
Oct 2011	Monash, "The Logical Argument Against Quantifier Variance", Monash University Staff Seminar
Oct 2011	Melbourne, "Denumerably Many Post-Complete Normal Modal Logics with Additional Proposi-
	tional Constants", Melbourne Logic Group.
Dec 2010	Melbourne, "Expressive Power, Mood and Actuality", Melbourne Logic Group.
Oct 2007	Melbourne, "The Range of Translations and the Problem of Maximality", Melbourne Logic Group.

Teaching

As Lecturer

S1 2014	Lecturer for PHIL20030 Meaning, Possibility and Paradox (University of Melbourne)
S2 2011	Guest Lecturer (Basic Modal Logic and Normal Modal Logics) for PHIL20030 Meaning, Possibility and
	Paradox (University of Melbourne)
S2 2011	Guest Lecturer for PHIL40013 Uncertainty, Vagueness and Disagreement Honours seminar on Fatalism
	(University of Melbourne)
S2 2010	Guest Lecturer (Nozick on Skepticism) for PHL1080 Time, Self and Mind.
S1 2010	Lecturer and Course Coordinator for PHL3590 Mind and Meaning (Monash University).

As Tutor

Responsible for running tutorials, marking continuous assessment and exams.

S1 2014	Head Tutor for UNIB10002 Logic: Language and Information (Melbourne University).
S2 2013	Tutor for PHIL20030 Meaning, Possibility and Paradox (University of Melbourne).
S2 2013	Tutor for ATS1838 Philosophy: Introduction C (Logic) (Monash University).
S1 2013	Tutor for ATS2866 Symbolic Logic (Monash University).
S1 2013	Head Tutor for UNIB10002 Logic: Language and Information (Melbourne University).
S1 2012	Head Tutor for UNIB10002 Logic: Language and Information (Melbourne University).
S1 2011	Tutor for ATS1833 Thinking (Monash University).
S2 2010	Tutor for PHL1080 Time, Self and Mind (Monash University).
S1 2008	Tutor for PHL1030 Thinking: Analysing Arguments (Monash University)

Service to the profession

Referee for Australasian Journal of Logic, Australasian Journal of Philosophy, Erkenntnis, Journal of Applied Non-Classical Logic, and Logique et Analyse.

Referees

LLOYD HUMBERSTONE
Reader
Monash University
Clayton, Victoria, Australia

e-mail: Lloyd.Humberstone@monash.edu

Professor Greg Restall Professor University of Melbourne Parkville, Victoria, Australia e-mail: restall@unimelb.edu.au

Assoc. Professor Catarina Dutilh Novaes Associate Professor University of Groningen Groningen, Netherlands e-mail: c.dutilh.novaes@rug.nl

PROFESSOR KAI F. WEHMEIER
Professor
University of California, Irvine
Irvine, California, United States of America
e-mail: wehmeier@uci.edu